Senior Software Engineer

Farzad Rafieimanesh

Website: www.Farzad-Rafieimanesh.com Email: farzad.rafieimanesh@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/farzad-rafieimanesh

Phone: +98 912 857 0030

Address: Avesta St, Sheikh Bahai Square, Tehran, Iran

Professional Summary

With over 23 years of experience, I am the Quality Control Manager at Behpersaz Jahan Company. I have managed large projects with professional teams, focusing on planning, risk management, and on-time delivery within tight budgets. I am proficient in Agile methodologies (RUP, Scrum) and have created custom documentation templates. My technical skills include Java, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, APIs, Oracle, and tools like GitHub, Jira, Jenkins, JUnit, Postman, and Selenium.

Work Experience

Behpardaz Jahan Company (Oct 2024 – Present)

- Due to the problem of the lack of a standard format for documenting system requirements and software testing in the company, custom, and standard technical documentation templates were created based on agile methodologies, resulting in uniform and highquality documents created by all teams in the company.
- Due to the lack of standard methods and patterns for manual and automated software testing, these methods and patterns were created using a variety of white and black box testing using Junit, Postman, and Selenium, which resulted in a 90% increase in software quality in the Java code and APIs section.
- Due to the lack of quality control of products in the company, standard procedures and instructions were developed and documents were created whereby source codes were subject to quality control, which increased customer satisfaction by 80%.

Al Research Engineer (May 2024 - Present)

The poor quality of medical images such as MRIs led me to use AI to improve patient body images in the PACS department and help in the early diagnosis of diseases by up to 70%. I also designed the Intelligent Medical Service Desk, which includes the following:

- Increased diagnostic accuracy: Using AI algorithms to reduce human errors.
- Remote access: Remote viewing and reporting for doctors.
- Integration with information systems: PACS integrates radiology information systems (RIS, HIS) and other medical automation.

Research and Development Company (Aug 2018 - Oct 2024)

Lack of oversight of outsourced projects to other private companies has resulted in a decline in the quality of products produced for our company. In these projects, as a software engineer on behalf of the company, I was responsible for the technical oversight of the development process of the following products using Agile, Scrum, and RUP methodologies. I was able to deliver documented, tested, and quality systems on time and within budget as per the RFP, proposal, and contract document and achieved 70% user satisfaction.

- Social and cultural affairs systems
- Virtual training platforms for government employees
- National fuel management system
- Crime and traffic violation management systems
- Police drug enforcement systems

Bahman Pardaz Company (Feb 2021 - Jun 2024)

• The lack of a proper system for allocating consumables and capital equipment to different parts of the army had caused problems. As a project manager, with a team of experts, I designed and implemented a web-based system with a three-tier architecture and microservices that was scalable using Java, Spring Boot, and Oracle, which improved equipment allocation by 95%. The problem of not providing integrated services to the people, including healthcare, livelihood assistance, consulting, and other such things, has created problems for the people and the government. As a project manager and business

analyst, I was able to implement a web-based system using the Scrum framework and Java and Oracle programming languages, and due to testing it with Selenium, Postman, and Junit, it became a quality product and improved the quantity and quality of services to the people.

 The Lack of an efficient system for assigning people to government jobs created dissatisfaction and problems for employees and officials. Designing and implementing a web-based system based on the country's laws increased the rate of assigning qualified people by 80%. The system was created using Java, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, and Oracle database and was successfully implemented with automated testing using Selenium and Postman.

Key Government & Enterprise Projects (Jun 2001 – Aug 2018)

- Traditional classroom and exam administration brought challenges such as distance and unfairness in exams. As a software analyst and designer, a web-based system using agile methodologies, Java programming language, and Oracle database was analyzed, designed, and implemented with a team collaboration that enabled online course definition, class attendance, and exam participation, reducing costs for students and professors by 80%.
- Removing unnecessary information in the office automation system slowed down the servers and reduced the speed of sending office correspondence. As an analyst, I used agile methods and Java programming to remove this information from the Oracle database. We designed a web-based system in collaboration with a team of programming experts, which increased the free space on the servers and improved the transmission of office correspondence in more than 20 provinces of the country.
- Filing cases, handling complaints, and issuing final rulings for tax collection were among
 the challenges of the Tax Affairs Organization. As a programmer, I improved the Tax
 Dispute Resolution Board system process by 90% using Delphi, SQLServer database,
 and client-server architecture.
- The aviation organization faced a major problem in keeping up-to-date information on pilots, training courses, and aircraft maintenance due to their large number and variety. As an analyst and Java and Spring Boot programmer, I, along with a team of specialists, analyzed, designed, and implemented a web-based system with a three-tier architecture and Oracle database over two years, which successfully covered all of the specialized processes of this organization 100%.

Technical Skills

Project Manager:

- Project Management: Ability to plan, execute, and oversee projects from start to finish.
- Time Management: Skill in scheduling and adhering to project timelines using Jira.
- Team Leadership: Capability to lead and manage cross-functional teams.
- Communication: Strong communication skills for interacting with various stakeholders.
- Risk Management: Ability to identify and manage project risks.
- Budgeting: Proficiency in managing project budgets and financial resources.

Methodologies and Modeling Tools: Agile, Scrum, RUP, UML, BPMN

Programming Languages: Java, Spring Boot, Delphi, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Databases: Oracle, PL-SQL, MySQL, SQL Server

Testing Tools: JUnit, Selenium, Postman

Improve software development processes: DevOps and CI/CD principles

Version Control: Jenkins, Git, GitHub

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering, Najaf Abad Azad University, Isfahan Province, Iran (Sep 1996 – Jul 2001)

Certifications & Training

- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) PMPiran (Apr 2021 May 2021)
- Diploma in English KishAir (Jun 2012 Feb 2014)